Ishtiaq Mahmood Amin

ANDROID / REACT NATIVE DEVELOPER · SOFTWARE ENGINEER

A-6, 543, East Kazipara, Mirpur-1216, Dhaka, Bangladesh

□ (+880) 1781-106123 | 💌 i4idrhine@gmail.com | 🖸 IronBlossom | 😩 IronBlossom | 🕲 iron_blossom | 🗖 IshtiaqMahmood_Amin

"The true delight is in the finding out rather than in the knowing."

Summary_

Current Android/React Native Developer at Offshore Software Development company Adaptive Enterprise Limited. Analytical and detail oriented programmer specialized in the android development, socket programming and both Object-oriented & Functional programming paradigm. A reader with steller communication skill who loves Linux, android kernel customization and enjoys tweaking the development environment to its efficiency. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks and learning new technologies and tools when needed.

Work Experience _____

Adaptive Enterprise Limited

Dhaka, Bangladesh

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Dec. 2014 - Present

- Developed, supervised and currently maintaining more than seven of NAPCO Security Technologies biggest state of the art apps to manage home security, home automation, video cameras on Android and React Native utilizing Socket Programming(TCP and UDP), Serial port communication (NDK), H.264 video decoding, Bluetooth LE(Low Energy), IPC, AIDL, Google Vision api, Realm for Android etc.
- Implemented an in-house stock exchange analysis app with seamless UX/UI following the Material Design guidelines with tools like MPAndroid-Chart, Realm for Android.
- Designed and developing a React Native app, that aggregates several reputated government/non-government banks, to make a secured payment rail in the national e-commerce field under DOER.

Cloudwell Limited Dhaka, Bangladesh

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Aug. 2013 - Dec. 2014

- Developed easy-to-use Android apps for the startup, facilitating Paywell's Payment infrastructure from Paywell Services app to in-house applications e.g. Paywell Distributor/Dealer/Collector/Territory Officer app.
- Provisioned backend developers with Servlet +php/Java bridge +Quartz Job Scheduler, by building an app that acts as tiny sms server for TeleTalk REB Bill Payment.
- Java Desktop application (jdk1.6+JavaFX) that pushes sms utilizing SilverStreet sms gateway.
- Worked with Telpo and partially developed Paywell application (with the provided SDK on Embedded-C) on 3 different embedded subsystem POS terminals (TPS300, KMY801B, MIL300)

AnnaNovas IT Dhaka, Bangladesh

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (ANDROID)

Oct. 2011 - Jun. 2013

- Built several apps using REST api, sqlite, custom views/controls, Google Maps API (v1), FCM/GCM(then Google C2DM) etc from ground up.
- Developed 3 inbuilt system apps and the launcher app that executes Linux shell commands for Polaroid Kids Tablet.

Professional Projects _____

Adaptive Enterprise Limited

Dhaka, Bangladesh

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Apr. 2007 - Sep. 2011

• Completed graduation with CGPA 2.97 from CSE Dept.

Education

AUST(Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Apr. 2007 - Sep. 2011

• Completed graduation with CGPA 2.97 from CSE Dept.

Presentation _____

DevFest Seoul by Google Developer Group Korea

Seoul, S.Korea

Presenter for <Hosting Web Application for Free utilizing GitHub, Netlify and CloudFlare>

Nov. 2017

- · Introduced the history of web technology and the JAM stack which is for the modern web application development.
- Introduced how to freely host the web application with high performance utilizing global CDN services.

6th CodeEngn (Reverse Engineering Conference)

Seoul, S.Korea

PRESENTER FOR < DEFCON 20TH: THE WAY TO GO TO LAS VEGAS>

Jul. 2012

· Introduced CTF(Capture the Flag) hacking competition and advanced techniques and strategy for CTF

Writing_

A Guide for Developers in Start-up

Facebook Page

FOUNDER & WRITER

Jan. 2015 - PRESENT

• Drafted daily news for developers in Korea about IT technologies, issues about start-up.

Extracurricular Activity

PoApper (Developers' Network of POSTECH)

Pohang, S.Korea

CORE MEMBER & PRESIDENT AT 2013

Jun. 2010 - Jun. 2017

- · Reformed the society focusing on software engineering and building network on and off campus.
- Proposed various marketing and network activities to raise awareness.

PLUS (Laboratory for UNIX Security in POSTECH)

Pohang, S.Korea

MEMBER

Sep. 2010 - Oct. 2011

- · Gained expertise in hacking & security areas, especially about internal of operating system based on UNIX and several exploit techniques.
- Participated on several hacking competition and won a good award.
- Conducted periodic security checks on overall IT system as a member of POSTECH CERT.
- Conducted penetration testing commissioned by national agency and corporation.